[WOMAN 10A screams]
Yeah. Very dead.
Have a look.
It was quite clearly a murder.
Murder?
So, William,
if you don't have any pressing
matters before we reach London,
how about a friendly competition
to see which of us
finds the culprit first?
[LESTRADE]
Huh? You're not serious!
This is a murder,
not one of your games!
I accept.
No doubt it'll prove
entertaining.
However,
this case seems more complicated
than at first glance.
[GROUP gasps]
[HOLMES]
John.
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
All right, then.
What's all the fuss?
[LESTRADE]
The transport police.
[gasps] What's the
meaning of this?
Right then, we're in charge
of this investigation!
Arrest this man!
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11B]
Aye!
[gasps] Wait a moment!
This blood.
It's from when someone
ran into me at the loo!
[WATSON]
I went back to my compartment,
and after a short while,
I noticed the stain.
Please believe me!
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11B] We'll
discuss it at headquarters.
Now, come along!
[LESTRADE]
Just a moment.
I am Inspector Lestrade
of Scotland Yard.
Oh. Their only
competent detective!
Right, uh... Anyhow,
this is consulting
detective Sherlock Holmes.
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
In the flesh?
[LESTRADE] And the man whom
you've cast your suspicion upon,
is his friend,
Doctor John H. Watson.
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
I had no idea.
Doctor Watson is not
the sort of man
who would commit
such a heinous crime.
I implore you to exercise
your best judgement.
Yes, but under the
circumstances--
[HOLMES grunts] This is
a waste of precious time!
You're the ones who don't
understand the circumstances,
you bollocks-for-brains!
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11B gasps]
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
Sir! What do you mean by that?
Wake up, man! As we speak,
the killer's still on the train!
Unless he's leapt from
a locomotive traveling
to London at a hundred
kilometres per hour!
The next station this train
stops at after leaving Doncaster
will be Grantham.
That's roughly 80
kilometers away.
Which leaves--
[WILLIAM]
Roughly 48 minutes.
[HOLMES]
Precisely!
If we don't discover the real
murderer by then, he'll escape!
Can the Transport
Police find them? Can they?
Well, we'll do our best...
[HOLMES grunts, chuckles]
Why not put us in charge?
Holmes has actually
solved a good number of cases.
What do you say we leave
the investigation up to him?
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
Inspector!
I don't care how famous
a detective he is.
Brother, I'm confused.
We had nothing to do
with this incident.
Then why get entangled
with Holmes?
We shouldn't.
That said,
an innocent man has fallen
under suspicion of murder.
Finding the real culprit,
and proving their guilt,
would prove impossible
for the transport police.
So naturally, we have to fulfill
our noblesse oblige, agreed?
Very well then. We'll help.
[LESTRADE,
TRANSPORT POLICE 11A gasp]
I'm telling you,
all we require is 48 minutes.
We'll have the whole case
figured out by then!
Isn't that right, Liam?
[LOUIS]
Liam? Rather chummy.
What are they? Friends?
Yes.
In fact, I suspect we won't even
need the full amount of time
to reach our findings.
Ah. Well, listen to you.
Athough this is little more
than a chance encounter,
I refuse to bring shame
to the Moriarty name
by standing idly by.
That sounds good to me!
We've a contest then.
Who can unmask
the culprit first.
Still treating this
like a damn game.
I'll allow it.
Only because Inspector
Lestrade has faith in you.
You'll have until
we reach the next station.
Much obliged.
However, we're
placing Doctor Watson
in our custody until any
new evidence comes to light.
Sherlock...
Let's be quick.
Time is of the essence.
You have read my mind.
Hey, wait, you don't have a key!
So how'd you open the door then?
Hah. Some policeman.
You mean you can't
even pick a lock?
So that's it. Just
about done here.
Have you found something that
will lead us to
the murderer, Holmes?
[HOLMES]
Yeah.
Here's what we know: The victim
is a jeweller from London.
Trevor Redwood.
The killer is male.
He boarded the train at
the terminus in Durham.
When the drugging slash
robbery went awry,
he knifed the victim.
If Redwood was drugged,
then that must mean murder
wasn't the sole motive!
Unmistakably.
Obviously.
[gasps, grunts]
[LESTRADE] As if one
Holmes wasn't enough!
Now there's two of them
with this Moriarty fellow.
I give. If you wouldn't
mind explaining...
[HOLMES]
Very well, as a favour.
Time is short, so I shall
only run through this once.
First off, the carpet
in this compartment
has two sets of
men's footprints.
One set belongs to the victim.
The other is from the Durham
man, measuring ten inches.
What makes you say Durham?
[HOLMES] Why not ask a certain
professor who resides there?
[LESTRADE]
They're muddied.
Indeed. It was
raining in Durham.
However, since our
first stop in York,
the weather has been clear.
Now I see. So we've narrowed
down the murderer's sex
and the station they boarded.
Additionally, this is what
Holmes was referring to.
If you'll observe.
Whisky... with a hint of more.
There is still the faint,
lingering aroma of chloral.
When mixed with alcohol,
it becomes a dangerous drug
which exhibits powerful
soporific effects.
Whatever means were used,
somebody had to have laced
the drink with the compound.
But why would they
drug the victim
before brutally stabbing them?
[HOLMES groans]
Because something happened which
the killer was not expecting.
Nothing more.
Without a doubt,
this was an unplanned murder.
If killing this man
was the true objective,
there would be no reason
to do so on a train
where escape would
be impossible.
More than likely,
the culprit drugged the victim
and attempted to rob him
whilst he was incapacitated.
[WILLIAM]
Either the chloral was too weak
or his tolerance too high.
Regardless, he awoke
during the theft.
Resulting in an unexpected
surprise for both.
[WILLIAM] Judging from
the shape of his wound
the weapon was a keen blade,
a knife of some sort.
And from the marks
left on the case,
the killer tried prying
it open with said knife.
[LESTRADE]
A knife, huh? I don't see one.
The murderer must
have left with it.
[WILLIAM]
The chances are quite high.
When the victim awakened,
a struggle ensued
during which
Redwood was stabbed.
The amount of blood must
have surprised the killer.
There are indications
he held his hand over
the wound to stop the bleeding.
[LESTRADE]
Quite so.
Despite there being no blood
on the victim's hands,
a handprint was left behind
It stands to reason he panicked
and forgot the
burglary all together.
Didn't attempt to hide the body.
Not to mention, he left behind
the whisky and the briefcase.
The knife and key are
the only things missing.
All the culprit
could think to do
was leave the room
and lock the door.
The crime scene indicates
that the culprit was flustered
by what transpired.
[HOLMES]
I'm in full agreement.
You're finished with
the crime scene?
Indeed. We have
all that we need.
Let's go, John--
Thirty-nine minutes remain.
[HOLMES]
Hm.
Lord Moriarty!
I brought the passenger list
for you to look at
along with each of the
compartment layouts!
Wonderful.
But first I have a few
questions to ask you.
[CREWMAN 11A]
Hm?
[LOUIS]
Holmes.
The one man in the world to whom
my brother pays due respect.
However, from
William's standpoint,
he's nothing more than a pawn.
And yet, the man addresses him
so casually, not to mention,
he dares to challenge
him to a contest.
Could he be any cheekier?
The moment he stops being
useful to us, I swear...
[WILLIAM]
Interesting.
Allow me to thank you.
You've been helpful.
[CREWMAN 11A] No need, my lord,
the pleasure was mine.
It was an honor, sir.
Have you found anything new?
Indeed.
Holmes will narrow down
who the culprit might be
by relying on
circumstantial evidence.
Who could have
gotten him to drink,
who could've left
the footprints.
As for me,
I have a different approach--
the psychological.
I'll look for clues to
profile the killer's mind.
[WILLIAM] As we've established,
the culprit was greatly alarmed
when the crime
didn't go as planned.
But he still managed
to lock the door as he left
out of fear of someone walking
by and discovering his crime.
Then at the lavatory,
the culprit stumbled
into Mister Watson.
Louis.
Why do you think the killer
went there in the first place?
They would be carrying the knife
and room key at that point.
If found with either,
they would be declaring
themselves the murderer.
So he must have gone there
to dispose of the evidence!
[WILLIAM]
Exactly. That's one reason.
The windows in the passengers
compartments don't open.
So he needed to throw
them from the washroom.
Once the tracks are searched,
no doubt both will be recovered.
[LOUIS]
And? What was the other reason?
[WILLIAM]
It's quite simple, really.
He wanted to wash the
blood off his clothes.
[LOUIS]
Yes. The victim's blood.
But if he tossed
out his clothing
along with the weapon
and key, then-- [gasps]
Right, he couldn't
dispose of his clothes,
otherwise he would
have stood out.
Therefore, we can assume
that he's still wearing them.
He had no other choice
but to wash them.
Holmes determined the killer was
male based on the footprints.
But he didn't narrow
it down further than that.
Rest assured,
soon he will realise the tracks
can be found everywhere.
Despite the difference in size,
the footprints remain identical.
All from one source.
[HOLMES] The shoes are
issued to the crewmen.
Of course. It makes sense.
A crewman would offer a
first-class passenger a drink.
And they couldn't get
rid of their jacket.
Let's not forget his gloves.
[WILLIAM] Each pair is white
and individually monogrammed.
Meaning, if he disposed
of his jacket and gloves,
he'd essentially be
confessing to the murder.
And after the killer went
to the washroom to clean
the blood off of his uniform,
he ended up bumping
right into Mister Watson.
Should we search for
the guilty party now?
There are six crewmen
aboard this train.
Once Holmes reaches
this conclusion,
he will gather them up for us.
Before he does, though, I will
need to meet each individually.
Just to be sure.
There it is an
outline of the crime
as Liam and I see it.
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
And us as well.
If he couldn't throw out
the blood-stained clothes.
He would be left with no
conceivable option other than
washing them off
in the loo's sink.
Yeah. Which means
the killer is
one of the crewmen.
That's our conclusion.
Both of you with a
ten-inch shoe size,
please step forward.
Now, if you gentlemen
wouldn't mind
letting us look at your gloves.
But why our gloves, sir?
Allow me.
Good, next.
[LESTRADE grunts] Your sleeves
are wet, open your hands.
Show me your gloves!
[CREWMAN 11F grunts]
[TRANSPORT POLICE, CREW gasp]
Red handed.
Passenger Car Attendant
Eddie Hawthorne,
you are the killer.
Eddie? How could
you do such a thing?
[CREWMAN 11D]
This is impossible!
[CREWMAN 11A]
It can't be.
Doctor Watson,
it seems we owe you an apology.
Please excuse us.
You're mad! Me?
Killing someone?
Believe me. It's mine.
I had an accident!
Prove it! Now take off
your gloves and show us!
Of course.
[LESTRADE]
What?
While working, I cut myself
through the gloves.
I was too busy to speak up.
[CREWMAN 11F] Please,
you have to believe me!
It's the truth! I'm innocent!
That is, of course unless
you have some other proof?
The man's
prevaricating, clearly.
I agree. Still, nothing
else implicates him.
Even after we recover the weapon
from the side of the tracks,
he could claim it
doesn't belong to him.
[WILLIAM]
This certainly is odd.
[gasps]
[HOLMES]
William?
You told us you hurt yourself
through the gloves.
Is that right?
Well, yes.
Then kindly explain...
How did blood land
on your eyeglasses?
[CREWMAN 11F gasping]
I-- That is...
Huh?
[WILLIAM] Injuring your palms,
whilst wearing gloves,
still doesn't explain how
blood got on the frames.
Unless
it landed there when you killed
Redwood in his compartment.
[CREWMAN 11F] No- I.
That's not the only clue.
There are far more.
If you would like,
I could point out each one.
[CREWMAN 11F grunts]
The manifest said
that Redwood was a jeweller.
I never meant to kill the man.
I just meant to--
[TRANSPORT POLICE 11A]
Eddie Hawthorne.
You're under arrest for murder!
Excellent.
We should arrive at Grantham
in three minutes or so.
Seems we made it in time,
Mister Holmes.
Liam, you scoundrel.
You're even better
at bluffing than I am.
[WILLIAM] My dear sir,
whatever do you mean?
[WILLIAM]
Well, we must take our leave.
[HOLMES]
Let's grab a bite sometime.
[LESTRADE]
Is this destiny?
A man, equal in
intellect to Holmes,
here as his contemporary.
Moriarty.
[LOUIS]
I'm impressed how you spotted
a blood stain that
small, Brother.
[WILLIAM] Well, I was
the one who put it there.
What?
I anticipated that the murderer
would try to be evasive.
[WILLIAM]
So I intervened.
Before Holmes
presented his case,
I met with each crewmember,
fabricating pretenses
to plant my blood on them
in various places.
[LOUIS]
If you hadn't been there,
the case wouldn't have resolved
before we reached the station.
So Holmes's endgame
isn't as strong as he thinks.
[WILLIAM] His method
would have been enough to
prove Hawthorne's
guilt at trial.
Whereas my method freed
Doctor Watson before then.
Holmes is far too trusting.
However, that's not
necessarily such a bad trait.
On the contrary, it's one
thing I like about him.
Plus, those two, they make
a rather good pair.
[WATSON]
Ironic, isn't it?
I was the one who told you to go
ahead and become a murderer.
But if you hadn't
been there for me
undoubtedly, I would've
been the one branded a killer.
Uh, John... I...
Ah... So, look.
Lately things haven't
been going my way.
You know?
But, as long as
you're okay with it
then I wouldn't mind us
teaming up again.
My word, is that really
your idea of an apology?
[HOLMES grumbles]
It would seem the great
detective is a mere mortal.
While I'm not sure what on earth
that's supposed to mean,
tell me, are we
a team again or aren't we?
[WATSON] Give me one of
your cigarettes, Sherlock.
As for the matches,
I can handle those.
I wouldn't be a good doctor if
I couldn't light a cigarette,
wouldn't you say?
[HOLMES laughs]
Doctor John Watson?
Making a joke?
For this to work you're
going to need a sense of humor!
[HOLMES laughs]
[MYCROFT]
Begging your pardon...
...but I am here
to make my report,
Your Majesty.
I look forward to hearing it.
As of now,
the situation is dire.
Unfortunately, regarding
the stolen documents,
the whereabouts remain unknown.
Whoever has them
in their possession,
they have yet to make
contact or list demands.
That is regretful,
considering they hold
one of Great Britain's
best kept secrets.
You're free to use whatever
means, no matter how ruthless.
Just retrieve those documents,
Sir Mycroft Holmes.
Yes, Your Majesty.